杰森 · 兰斯托夫: 好的，我们的第一部分是创建
&gt;&gt; Jason Lengstorf: All right, so our
first piece here is going to be to create
一个表格，这样我们就可以追踪人们在搜索什么。
a form, so that we can track
what people are searching for.
他们需要能够实际输入一个搜索词，然后我们想采取
They need to be able to actually input
a search term and then we wanna take
提交表单时，重写 URL。
that search term on submitting the form,
rewrite the URL with it.
这意味着我们需要使搜索词 url 友好。
So that means that we need to make
the search term URL-friendly.
所以我们要做一点点的字符串咀嚼，使工作，然后我们将
So we're gonna do a little bit of string
munging to make that work and then we'll
也可以使用导航助手函数使用 Gatsby 进入编程导航。
also get into programmatic navigation with
Gatsby using the navigate helper function.
首先，我们要进入源文件夹
So first, we're just gonna hop
into our source folder and
让我们创建一个组件文件夹，在其中，我们将创建一个表单。
let's create a components folder and
inside of that, we'll create a form.
这是我们的搜索表格。
And this is gonna be our search form.
所以我要进口反应从反应。
So I'm gonna import React from React.
然后我们要建立我们的表格，常量表格，还有
And then we're gonna set up our form,
so const form, and
它会返回一些东西，导出违约。
that will return something,
that will export default.
Jason Lengstorf: 好的，在我们的表单中，我们只需要设置一个表单。
&gt;&gt; Jason Lengstorf: Okay, so inside of
our form, we want to set up just a form.
然后，onSubmit，我们需要做一些事情。
And then, onSubmit,
we need to do something.
让我们创建一个名为 handleSubmit 的函数。
So let's create a function
called handleSubmit.
杰森 · 兰斯托夫: 这将会起到一些作用
&gt;&gt; Jason Lengstorf: And
that's gonna do something, and
然后在我们的表格里，我们要建立一个标签。
then inside of our form,
we're going to set up a label.
在标签里面我们会说按名字搜索。
And inside of the label
we'll say search by name.
然后我们将添加类型文本的输入。
And then we'll add
an input of the type text.
我们会给它起个名字。
We will give it a name of name.
然后我们设定一个值。
And we'll set a value.
因为我们想要控制价值，我们想要做出反应来管理它。
And because we want to control the value,
we want React to manage it.
我们不希望它被用户管理。
We don't want it to be
kind of user-land managed.
我们将使用 use state hook。
We're going to use the use state hook.
那么让我们设置一下 use state，然后我们说 value。
So let's set up use state,
and we'll say value.
设定值。
set value.
这将是使用状态的结果，我们只需要空白开始。
And that's going to be the result of use
state, and we'll just start it out empty.
所以我们这里的价值就是价值。
So our value here is going to be value.
然后在改变的时候，我们要处理输入,
And then on change,
we're going to handle input,
这是另一个辅助函数。
which will be another helper function.
杰森 · 兰斯托夫: 然后在下面，在我们的标签之外,
&gt;&gt; Jason Lengstorf: And
then below, outside of our label,
我们要加一个按钮。
we're going to add a button.
那个按钮将会是提交类型。
That button is gonna
be of the type Submit.
上面只写着搜索。
And it'll just say search.
所以，这就是我们最需要的。
So, that is most of what we need.
但现在我们需要做到这一点，我们需要处理输入。
But now we need to make this,
we need to handle input.
我们可以设置常量处理输入，这也是一个函数。
So we can set up const handle input,
and that's also gonna be a function.
Jason Lengstorf: 所以为了处理输入,
&gt;&gt; Jason Lengstorf: So
for handling the input,
我们真正要做的是得到当前值，然后把它放进去。
what we really wanna do is just get
the current value and drop it in.
所以我们可以得到事件和
So we can just get the event and
然后我们将值设置为事件目标值。
then we're gonna set the value
to event target value.
这样我们就可以在字段中输入
And that will allow us to
type in the field, and
当我们输入时，它会更新状态。
that'll update the state whenever we type.
这是一个非常标准的控制反应输入的方式。
It's a pretty standard way of
controlling inputs in React.
如果您使用类组件完成了这项工作,
If you've done this
using class components,
美国房地产挂钩是如此的新鲜空气的呼吸方面
the useState hook is such
a breath of fresh air in terms of
控制输入是多么的简单。
how simple it makes it to control inputs.
我们没有写出特殊的类方法，然后把它绑定到这些方法上
We're not writing out special class
methods and then binding this to them and
做这些事情就像，你知道,
doing all these things that are like,
you know,
一旦你记住了它们的工作原理，它们就变得容易了，但这并不容易。
they're easy once you've memorized
how they work but it's not easy.
看起来有点时髦，因为当你看着它们的钩子时
useState is a little bit funky to look at
because when you look at hooks they've got
这些数组的破坏设置，并
these kind of array destructuring set up,
and
感觉有点像魔术。
they kind of feel like magic a little bit.
但是一旦这个模型开始运作，事情就变得简单明了了
But once the the model kind of sets in,
it really makes things straightforward and
陈述性的，非常非常适合工作。
declarative, which is really,
really wonderful to work with.
在我们的处理，提交，我们想要做的是，再一次，我们将得到一个事件。
In our handle, submit, what we want to do,
is again, we're going to get an event.
但是在这种情况下，我们要防止形式去任何地方。
But in this case, we wanna prevent
the form from going anywhere.
我们不想导航到另一个页面或刷新页面或
We don't wanna like navigate to
another page or refresh the page or
默认情况下表单会做的任何事情。
any of the things that forms
will typically do by default.
所以我们要做事，阻止违约
So we're gonna do event.preventDefault,
and
这样可以防止表单，你知道，把我们的 React 应用吹走
that will prevent the form from,
you know, blowing away our React app and
带我们去，或者刷新页面什么的。
taking us to, or
like refreshing the page or anything.
在那之下，我们需要把搜索
Underneath that,
we need to turn the search
字符串放到一个 url 友好的查询中。
string into a URL-friendly query.
然后,
And then,
我们真的需要，杰森 · 兰斯托夫: 改变
we need to actually,
&gt;&gt; Jason Lengstorf: Change
网址来匹配搜索结果。
the URL to match our search results.
杰森 · 兰斯托夫: 所以，为了把它变成一个搜索友好的查询,
&gt;&gt; Jason Lengstorf: So,
to turn this into a search-friendly query,
我们要在这里取值，这可能是任何东西。
we're gonna take the value up here,
which could be anything.
所以我实际上要做的是，让我们把这个放到屏幕上，这样我们就能看到它了。
So what I'll actually do is, let's just
get this on the screen, so we can see it.
然后我们开始学习如何处理表单。
And then we'll start playing
with how to handle the form.
让我们来看看这个。
So let's get this.
我们将使用自动导入，因为这很简洁。
We're going to use that
auto-import because that's neat.
然后在这里，这就是我们想要的。
And then up here, that does what we want.
实际上并不需要那个链接。
Don't need that link actually.
所以，让我们把它从那里拿出来。
So let's get that out of there.
现在我有了一张表格。
And so now I've got a form.
让我们开始吧。
So let's start this up.
我要去做 netlify dev。
I'm going to do netlify dev.
杰森 · 兰斯托夫: 好的，成功，好的，现在我们有了一个表格，和
&gt;&gt; Jason Lengstorf: Okay, success, all
right, and so now we've got a form, and
我们可以在里面输入，它就会按照我们预期的方式运行。
we can type into it and
it's doing what we expect.
如果我把控制台移到这里,
So if I move the console down here,
所以我们可以看到它，然后把它变大
so we can see it and
then make it much bigger so
我们可以读它，我可以把它设置为
we can read it, I can set this by
默认为控制台日志值。
default to console log value.
让我们找一块地来搜索，它会记录一些东西。
So let's just take a field and
search it, and it's gonna log something.
好的很好。
Okay, good.
所以我们的表格。
So our form does submit.
它正确地处理提交，它不刷新页面或任何东西。
It handles the submit properly,
it's not refreshing the page or anything.
接下来我们要做的是
So the next thing that we want
to do is what if somebody
像 Rick & Morty 之类的,
types in like Rick &amp; Morty,
something like that,
我们不能只是喜欢链接到那里。
that would break any URL,
we can't just like link to that.
在我们正在进行的查找上下文中，它也不是特别有用。
It's also not particularly useful in the
context of the lookup that we're doing.
因为我们知道我们的 API 是基于文本的搜索,
So because we know that our
API's a text-based search,
我们不需要任何特殊角色，这样就大大简化了我们的工作。
we don't need any special characters, so
that drastically simplifies our job here.
所以我想做的第一件事就是
So the first thing that I want to do is,
I'm just gonna go ahead and
我们先创建一个新的变量,
let's start by creating a new variable,
which is gonna initially be the value,
然后我要做几个变形。
but then I'm gonna do
a couple of transformations.
我把它改成小写,
I'm gonna change it to lowercase,
我要把开头和结尾的空白部分都剪掉。
I'm gonna trim any white space
from the beginning and end.
然后我们来讨论正则表达式替换。
Then I'm gonna get into regular
expression replacement.
所以我们要用正则表达式。
So we'll use a regex.
我要创建一个集合，并说任何不是
And I'm going to create a set and
say anything that is not
一个单词字符或者一个空格，Jason Lengstorf: And
a word character or a space,
&gt;&gt; Jason Lengstorf: And
我们要把它推向全球，它将被一无所有的东西所取代。
we're gonna go global with that,
it's going to be replaced with nothing.
所以我们基本上就是把所有的
So we're basically going through and
stripping out any
特殊字符，任何非空白的空白，都在里面。
special characters,
any non-space white space, all in.
这就是字母 a 到 z 和数字0到9。
And so that's the letters A through Z and
the number zero through nine.
这就是斜杠小写 w 所允许的。
That's what the slash lowercase w allows.
空格字符就是空格字符。
And the space character is
just the space character.
所以不是新行，不是制表符，不是那样的。
So not new lines, not tabs,
nothing like that.
所以我们对允许什么有很多限制。
So we're being pretty restrictive
about what we're allowing.
然后，因为我想传递这个网址，我不想要一堆丑陋的,
And then, because I wanna pass this in
the URL and I don't want a bunch of ugly,
比如，百分之20在这里，我也要取代所有的空格字符。
like, percent 20s in there, I'm going
to also replace any space character.
我们会做一个或多个，以防有人说，比如,
And we will do one or more,
just in case somebody says, like,
里克15个空格，然后莫蒂，我们不喜欢15个连字符，这是愚蠢的。
Rick 15 spaces and then Morty,
we don't like 15 hyphens, that's silly.
所以我们要做一个或多个空格字符。
So we're going to do one or
more space characters.
再一次，我们将用它走向全球，我们将用连字符代替它。
And again, we'll go global with that,
and we'll replace it with a hyphen.
现在我有了这个问题。
So now I have this query.
所以让我们控制台记录它。
So let's console log it.
杰森 · 兰斯托夫: 好的，在这样做之后，我应该得到的是
&gt;&gt; Jason Lengstorf: Okay, so
upon doing that, what I should get is for
一个普通的查询，比如我输入一个人的名字,
an average query,
like if I just type someone's name,
没有什么真正的改变，但如果我开始添加一些无意义的东西
nothing really changes, but
if I start adding a bunch of nonsense in
这里，杰森 · 兰斯托夫: 它剥离它只是
here,
&gt;&gt; Jason Lengstorf: It strips it to just
实际的字母字符，这样做的方式将工作在一个网址。
the actual letter characters, and does so
in a way that would work in a URL.
这就是我们想要的，对吧？
So that's kind of what we're after, right?
我们需要一些东西，我们可以把它放在一个网址，使它可以链接，和
Is we want something that we can put
in a URL and make it linkable, and
我们会在结果会议上解决这个问题。
we'll deal with reversing
this in the results session.
所以现在我们知道它们在那里它在做我们想做的事,
So, now that we know these are there,
and it's doing what we want,
我们可以用这个查询重写历史。
we can use this query
to rewrite our history.
为了做到这一点，我们将使用《了不起的盖茨比》中的导航助手。
And to do that, we're going to use
the navigate helper from Gatsby.
所以我们要从盖茨比引进导航系统,
So we're gonna import
navigate from Gatsby,
在我们的联络人体内,
and inside of our handler,
我们只是去导航。
we're just going to navigate.
Jason Lengstorf: 要搜索，我们将使用查询。
&gt;&gt; Jason Lengstorf: To search,
and we'll use the query.
然后，我们也会把它传递下去。
And then,
we're also going to pass that down.
所以我们将它作为查询放入状态。
So we'll put it in the state as query.
詹森 · 兰斯托夫: 这意味着我们可以拉动我们已经创建的状态
&gt;&gt; Jason Lengstorf: So this means that
we can pull the state that we've created
不需要解析 url 或者其他任何东西，直接从查询中删除,
right out of the query without
having to parse the url or anything,
当它是一个本地点击。
when it's a local click.
当有人发送链接时，我们仍然需要解析 URL。
We'll still have to parse the URL
when someone sends a link.
但我们可以跳过一些工作如果有人在本地做的话,
But we can skip some work in the case
that somebody's doing it locally,
这将是，真的，最常见的用例。
which will be, really,
the most common use case.
所以在这个过程中，我们每次搜索的时候,
So upon doing this,
what should happen is whenever we search,
所以我会说，让我们说，Morty，我们的网址刚刚改变，现在它说斜杠 Morty。
so I'll say, let's say, Morty, our URL
just changed, and now it says slash Morty.
如果我在这里放一堆垃圾
And if I put a bunch of junk in here and
然后说 Rick，它被编辑给 Morty dash Rick。
then say Rick,
it gets edited to Morty dash Rick.
酷。
Cool.
好吧，这就是我们想要的。
Okay, that's doing what we want.
所以，让我们保存我们的工作。
So let's save our work.
然后我们会让结果页面工作。
And then we'll get that
results page working.